Asher Hounsell

University of Toronto

BASc. In Engineering Science

Electrical & Computer Engineering Major

Engineering Business Minor

Contact

Phone

(613) 331-6640

E-mail:

asher.hounsell@mail.utoronto.ca

LinkedIn

Asher Hounsell

Website

asherhounsell.ca

Key Skills

Tenacious Work Ethic

Need for Learning

Problem Solving

Communication & Interpersonal Skills

Leadership & Teamwork

Languages/Tools/Libraries:

Python, JavaScript, TypeScript, C/C++, ARM Assembly, Verilog, MATLAB, SQL, CSS, Ignition, Vena, Azure

Design Experience:

User Experience, big data systems, Ul Architecture, SCADA & HMI Tools

Projects:

Multithreaded Server in C, Built Website using React, Balancing Robot Using IO in ARM My passion in life is **learning** and **solving opportunities**. As I gain more technical experience in my career, I further believe that my soft skills – being **willing to learn** and having a **tenacious work ethic** – are my most valuable assets. With these qualities, I know that I can adapt to any new situation by relying on my initiative to learn the necessary skills and have the dedication to follow through with the project until it is rigorously complete. I look forward to applying this drive along with my **leadership**, **teamwork**, and expanding technical skills to aid a team in solving any complex engineering problem or opportunity.

Work History

Associate Solution Manager | Vena Solutions 16 Months (2022/05 – 2023/08)

- Working in the development segment of the presales team I built custom proof of concept software and integrations, contributing to over \$230,000 won ARR.
- I built these custom solutions between many different platforms using a variety of tools, including Vena, Excel, Power BI, ScriptLab, Azure, Power Automate, Javascript, & Python, in a very agile & self-driven environment which I thrived in.
- After working many deals and building customer trust in some very complex use cases, my technical and problem-solving ability was recognized by transitioning my workload to be self-instructed innovation to push the agenda of what is possible for our product.
- I then created many complex solutions that were not previously possible by making complex integrations into the product with JavaScript and connections to Azure, enabling algorithms to solve business use cases for ML forecasting, process automations, global product allocation optimization, and optimal resource allocation.
- I was then trusted to present these technical builds to clients in an understandable way, answering client questions and building customer trust to close complex deals.
- Some of my most notable projects at Vena were:
 - Won a \$135k ARR deal by use of novel iterations exploit to solve a previously unsolvable use case for a customer, which increased deal size dramatically.
 - Created a configurable algorithm for global product & project resource allocation, built in JavaScript & iteratively in Excel, and baked into commonly used **demoware** that was **highly praised**.
 - o Azure ML Forecasting & Google Suite Integrations to Demoware

Engineering Intern – Digitization Lead | Goodyear 4 Months (2021/05 – 2021/09)

- Using SCADA/HMI software Ignition, SQL & python, I lead the digitization of the most technologically advanced tire manufacturing plant in Goodyear.
- I developed a UI & backend to display information from every machine and IT service in the plant, allowing engineers/directors to monitor traceable real-time and historical data to maximize manufacturing efficiency throughout the plant.

Education

University of Toronto | Engineering Science: Electrical and Computer Engineering

2019/08 - 2023/04

Engineering Science is a division of the Engineering Faculty which places a higher focus on **rigor** and is an **enriched program** that provides students with excellent preparation for professional engineering related careers.

International Baccalaureate Programme | KCVI

2014/09 - 2019/05

The International Baccalaureate Programme is an enriched education programme teaching students to think **critically**, **independently**, and how to **inquire** with care & logic.

Accomplishments

- Finished first year of Engineering Science with High Distinction.
- **IB Award** Highest overall grade in KCVI's International Baccalaureate Programme.
- For **DECA**, a business, leadership and entrepreneurship club I achieved **international qualifier** in 2017, and **international champion** in 2018 and 2019.
- For **HOSA**, a medical science club, for which I was the founder of my school's local chapter, I was named **national champion**, qualifying internationally.